Dustin Vorac

dustin.vorac@gmail.com
(614)546-8688
Chicago, IL, USA
linkedin.com/in/dustin-vorac | github.com/dvorac

SUMMARY

I am a frontend-focused fullstack engineer with a jack-of-all-trades career history. I've worked across several industries including real estate, banking, and agricultural technology.

I find success and fulfillment by leading small engineering teams to deliver quality software on time, and with a focus on balancing the immediate needs of a product with the long-term needs of a company.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

EXCELERAS LLC (Chicago, Illinois) January 2023 - October 2024

- Created several features for a REO Servicing application that added business value to our real estate agent user's businesses, including an integration with a third-party vendor (BlueHammer by Bluebook International).
- Led development and agile user story organization of a small project to expand the reach of our Angular app to existing
 customers who were still using the older version of the application. Worked with stakeholders to allocate appropriate
 resources to the project to ensure it was completed on a tight timeline.
- Led efforts to upgrade the company's coding practices and developer experience, including promoting and teaching about Git version control (we used TFS), and promoting better code review practices (code reviews were not enforced).

Engineering Manager, Business Platform Team

AMOUNT (Chicago, Illinois) December 2020 - June 2022

- Led a team of 4 developers to perform incremental improvements to the company's back-office suite of applications dispute and complaint processing apps, and helpdesk and user admin tools. Maintained applications built as React
 frontends with Ruby on Rails backends with APIs designed in GraphQL, and Node.js applications attached to Postgres
 databases.
- Encouraged team engineers to grow their skillsets. Ushered them to opportunities to try new techstacks, such as feeding
 web developers opportunities to try Ruby on Rails development. Delivered guidance when they had issues or thorny
 technical problems.
- The suite of applications my team was responsible for were a mess of 5-year-old spaghetti code. I maintained and improved a running backlog of tasks for the team to pay down that tech debt. Over time, Developed technical documentation for the suite.

Associate Engineer, Avant Mobile Team

AMOUNT (Chicago, Illinois) May 2019 - December 2020

- Began my experience in React Native as a team engineer for the Avant Personal Banking application. I had never touched
 Typescript, React, nor GraphQL before this! Started contributing code in a few weeks on a techstack I had never experienced
 before.
- Led and independently developed a feature to allow credit card payments for loan products on the mobile app. This feature was complex and involved bypassing non-PCI-compliant systems within the business to work effectively and securely.

Senior Technical Consultant

SOLSTICE (Chicago, Illinois) July 2013 - May 2019

Discover Financial Services - Discover Virtual Assistant

• Chatbot for customer questions backed by Google DialogFlow NLP and AI engine. Lead team in design and development of PCF SpringBoot app middleware for the bot.

Fifth Third Bank - Momentum

• Android and iOS app to help people pay down their student debt. Basically, Robinhood for student loans. Lead the development of the Android app from conception to version 1 release.

John Deere - MyOperations

• Operations monitoring app for farm managers, native Android and iOS. Lead team of four developers to develop and design both platforms from scratch. Created mocked API service to aid development when production APIs were delayed.

The Northern Trust - Private Passport

• Android developer on a personal banking app. Included money transfer, photo-check-deposit, and push notifications.

Software Developer

SAFELITE AUTOGLASS (Columbus, Ohio) February 2010 – May 2013

- Mobile Blackberry/Android application ("MRM") for submitting paperwork for mobile service technicians. Featured push
 messaging, store-and-forward message reliability, secure credit card authorization, Bluetooth printer peripheral interfaces,
 smooth-stroke signature capture before those were commonly available in cloud systems! 4000+ users.
- Developed expansions to admin functions for the company's internal logistical tool, "MDM", which allowed dispatchers to plan technicians routes and equipment needs in advance.

EDUCATION

OHIO STATE UNIVERSITY, Columbus, Ohio

B.S., Electrical & Computer Engineering, 2010

SKILLS

Web: Angular, ASP.NET, React, GraphQL, Node.js, Nx, Webpack, Babel, Ruby on Rails, Express.js, Java SpringBoot

Mobile: React Native, Android, iOS

Languages: C#, Typescript, Javascript, Ruby, Java, Kotlin, Swift, VB, Bash

Cloud: Azure Devops, AWS - EC2, Route 53, IAM, Lambda, S3

CI/CD: Docker, Buildkite, Jenkins

Databases: SQL Server, Postgres, Oracle

VCS: Git, Github, TFS

Architectures: Monoliths, Microservices, REST, SOAP, MVC

Middleware: Oauth